Darko Iliev

Marital status Married, father of three children| Driving license Category A and B

Profile

Enthusiastic and organized professional with 14 years working experience in the field of Pharma, public health, non-government organizations, and family medicine. Effective leader and team member, supporting team members in alignment with project and organizational goals. English and German speaking, with international and intercultural experience. Skilled problem-solver and multi-tasker. Responsible, friendly, loyal.

Education

June 2001	High School: Josip Broz Tito - Skopje, Macedonia Degree: Gymnasium diploma;
2001 - 2007	Medical Faculty, University "St. Cyril and Methodius" Skopje R. Macedonia; Degree: Medical doctor, Average grade 8.5/10;
2009 -2013	Residency of Family Medicine, Medical Faculty University "St. Cyril and Methodius" Skopje R. Macedonia;
	March 2013 - Degree: Family Medicine Specialist
2015 - Present	School for Doctoral Studies, Medical Faculty, University "St. Cyril and Methodius" Skopje R. Macedonia
	Work thesis: Opportunistic screening for Diabetes type 2 in primary healthcare. Average grade 9.5
2018 - 2022	Master of Business Administration University of Sheffield International Faculty, CITY College - Health management. Dissertation with Distinction

Experience

FEB 2020 - DEC 2020

EMPLOYER: Roche Macedonia POSITION: Medical Ecosystem Partner KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Create and lead pre-launch strategy for Polatuzumab vedotin for DLBCL
 Supporting Onco-Hemato Franchise teams medical supervision of marketing activities
- Scientific communication with key HCP's in University clinic of Hematology,
- Scientific support for Market Access in discussions with key stakeholders (MoH, HIF)
- Mi Atlas Lead support clinic of Hematology and Oncology for clinical questions using academic literature (Uptodate and Roche library)
- Trainings on ZincMaps; PHC; PVG,

JUNE 2008 - FEB 2020

EMPLOYER: Private health organisation (PHO): Med.Izgrev,

POSITION: Family Medicine Specialist, Provider of Health Care Services and Manager of the Healthcare Facility

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:

Healthcare provider of 1000 patients, practicing Evidence Based Medicine. Holistic
approach to management of non-chronic and chronic diseases, emergency conditions
management, health prevention and health promotion. Administrative management,
procurement of medicine, maintenance of the private health organisation, audit of the
work.

OCTOBER 2010 - PRESENT

NGO MERC (www. merc.mk) Founded: 01.2010

POSITION: Founder, President Duties and Responsibilities

- MERC's organizational structure, operational policies and other processes are effectively delivered and strategic objectives defined by the Executive Board are followed
- Strengthen performance management by tracking Key Performance Indicators across the organization;
- Represent MERC, in-front of the society, stakeholders and partners ensuring its role within the scope of its influence,
- Prepare financial and program reports to the Board of MERC

Notable projects:

April 2012 - MARCH 2017, Successful collaboration with :Global Fund to Fight HIV/ AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria grants, (GFATM) and Ministry of Health - Role : Coordinator of project "Education for Tuberculosis of patients and member of their families and Education for tuberculosis for children in primary high schools"

April 2014 - April 2015 Successful collaboration with:Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ) GmbH - Role : Coordinator of project

"Establishment of national intersectional TB/HIV coalition and development of civil society in Macedonia in order to support the activities of GFATM in Macedonia"

... more info at merc.mk

DEC 2016 - PRESENT

WEB 3

Key activities:

- Venture Investor Scout startup crypto companies with potential to disrupt current financial and technology infrastructure, early investor in : Holochain, Zilliqa, Nash.io, Cardstack, Synthetix (Heaven), Ocean Protocol, RSK, crypto.com and more Actively contributing to their teams and communities;
- Part of tier 1 crypto communities, wide personal network in the ecosystem.
- Conducting due diligence, deep understanding of the blockchain technology, power user in the DEFI space.
- Active user of multiple platforms. Experience in big position trading. Skilled technical analysis on tradingview pro platform
- Keep track of the Non-fungible tokens space

Educational activities, Association Leadership Roles and Membership

- 2012 2018 Educator, Mentor, Department of Family Medicine, Medical Faculty, Skopje,
 Delivering lectures and clinical skills exercises to students and residents
- 2018 2020 Member of the National Commission for Tuberculosis by the Ministry of Health
- 2016 2017 General Secretary of Association of general practitioners in Macedonia
- 2011 2021 Member of the board of the Association of general practitioners in Macedonia
- 2013 2020 Accountant of the Association of general practice/family medicine of South East Europe
- 2013 Level 1; 2014 Level 2: LEONARDO EURACT Trainer level 1 and 2 Teaching courses for teachers
- 2011 2017 : European Resuscitation Council Advanced Life Support / Full Instructor

Publications

- Screening for Diabetes Type 2 in Primary Health Care Darko Iliev, Petranka Mishevska, Natasha Ilieva Maced Med Electr J. 2015 Dec 05; 2015;50020:6
- Comparison of clinical and inflammatory parameters of metabolically healthy and unhealthy
 obese with healthy lean body individuals in Turkish adults. Yasemin Turkera, Davut Baltacib,
 YasinTurkerc, Serkan Ozturkd, **Darko Iliev**e, Yunus Cem Sarifuzelf, Mehmet Harun Delerf,
 Fatih Alasang Acta Medica Mediterranea, 2015, 31: 201
- How much knowledge is healthy? Results of Knowledge, Attitudes and Practices on tuberculosis survey among ethnic minorities in Republic of Macedonia Dance Gudeva Nikovska, Kiril Soleski, **Darko Iliev**, Natasa Nikolovska Stankovic April 2014 Book of Abstract at UPHA's 5th European Conference on Migrant and Ethnic Minority
- Health Assessment of health services in potential municipalities for implementing PAL (practical approach to lung health) with special focus on primary health care and the burden of respiratory diseases. - Darko Iliev, Kiril Soleski - Report for Ministry of Health, Skopje,2013
- Tuberculosis in Macedonia New Public Health Interventions and Challenge Iliev Darko.
 Aleksioska N, Mujovik E .Tuberculosis in Macedonia New Public Health Interventions and Challenge .Abstract book, 28th International Medical Student Scientific Congress, May, 2005

Certificates and trainings

- "Boris Trajkovski" Executive MBA Scholarship for the Academic Year 2018-19
- Open Medical Institute Salzburg Medical Seminars Diabetes April 2017
- Congress of the Society of General and Family Medicine Teachers (DNOOM) Tertiary Prevention of Neurological, Psychological and Oncological Diseases in Family Medicine - march 2017
- Capacity Building for Sustainable Health Care Programs in South Eastern Europe Dubrovnik,
 Croatia 12-14 March 2015; Presentation: Brief overview of challenges in health care system in Macedonia
- Tailored Implementation for chronic diseases (TICD) Workshop, Warsaw, Poland 7-8 October 2014
- Tools for scientific work John Hopkins School Of Public Health Online course with distinction, 01 -31 May 2014
- European Academy of Teachers in General Practice: Leonardo EURACT course Level 2 Skopje, 3-5
 April 2014
- TB Regional Advocacy Training, TB Coalition Europe, Paris, France 25 October 02 November 2013
- European Pain Pathways Recommendations Active citizenship Network at EESC European Economic and Social Committee, Representing MERC Brussels, Belgium, 22-23 October 2013
- Chronic Pain in the EU Working Population, Work group: Best Practices in Europe: Brussels, Belgium, 16 May 2013
- Wolfheze Workshops 2013 May, Presentation: TB activities of NGO's in Macedonia / den Haag, Netherlands 29-31 May 2013

- III Conference of Association of General Practice/ Southeastern Europe, Presentation: Finances and primary health care / Belgrade, Serbia 07-10 April 2013
- European Academy of Teachers in General Practice: Leonardo EURACT course Level 1Krakow, Poland 21-23 March 2013
- Operational Research Training in Tuberculosis STOP TB Partnership Expert, Skopje, Macedonia, 12-15 November 2012
- Active Citizenship Network in Rome (ACN), Training: Advocacy, communication and social mobilization (ACSM), Italy for Rome, Italy, 26-28 April 2012
- Salzburg Seminars Open Medical Institute and the American Austrian Foundation, Salzburg, Austria 03-09 June 2011
- Preparation of application for funds from projects funded of the European union Technical Assistance for Civil Society Organizations, Struga, 4-5 May 2011
- European Resuscitation Council, Advanced Life Support Full Instructor Novi Sad, Serbia 4-6 April 2011
- Alleghenies Krankenhaus der Stadt Wien Emergency Medicine department Stipend for best students who speak German; Supported by the Lions Club 01-30 September 2007

IT Skills

- Created first national Windows based Bulletin Board System on Wildcat 5.0 BBS platform named "TOP10 BBS" (1999)
- Working as a Family Doctor found and reported bug on the computer software from the Health insurance Fund (2009) closing critical security bug using Hex editor;
- Contributor to several web projects (diabetes.mednet.mk;tuberkuloza.mk; semejnamedicina.mednet.mk, merc.mk)
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO) worked SEO for website mortgagerefinance.com achieved 1st position in period April-May 2011 for the keyword - "mortgage refinance" and several top 1-5 positions for related keywords.
- web development in Wordpress from scratch.

• Languages

English (excellent speaking and understanding, MBA at Sheffield)

German (basic speaking, intermediate understanding - 6 years private and public courses)

Russian (basic understanding and speaking - 3 years public and private courses)

Mother tongue(s) Macedonian;

Interests and hobbies

- tennis, bicycle riding, running, listening audiobooks, mending stuff, travel

^{*}References upon request.